# **Emmanuel Ezekiel**

### Front-End Enginee

+2348135610471 | Lagos State, Nigeria | <u>emmanuelezekiel228@gmail.com</u> | <u>http://www.linkedin.com/in/emmanuel-ezekiel</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

A skilled front-end developer with over 3 years of expertise working with technologies such as Redux, React, as well as languages such as Javascript, CSS, and HTML with extensive knowledge of UI/UX, and agile methodology. Experienced in Proven ability to transform wireframes and high-level designs into semantic, accessible frontend interfaces of complex web apps, as well as developing reusable UI components

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript/ES6+, TypeScript

Technologies/framework: Reactjs, React Native, Nextjs, Nodejs, Redux, Express, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Scss, Restful Apis, styled component, graphql

Tools: Git version control, Npm, Figma, Babel, Webpack, Jira, jest, Git & Github.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Visqorium Labs

Frontend Engineer (Remote)

Abuja State, Nigeria
April 2022– Present

- Built UI component in React js to digitize the process of global trade.
- Developed a custom React-based framework to create scalable and agile solutions which reduced build times by 25%.
- Reviewed code from the rest of the team, occasionally avoiding bugs and suggesting improvements when possible.
- Developing a flexible and well-structured front-end architecture, implementing new and existing APIs
- <u>Technologies</u>: React js, Styled-component, css3, Redux, Node js, MongoDB, jest

### Spend-WiseNg

Frontend Engineer (Remote)

Lagos State, Nigeria

Dec 2021- March 2022

- Created and launched a service that allows users to manage their personal finance
- Assisted in translating UI/UX design and wireframe into high-quality code.
- Discovered and fixed a complex bug in legacy code that was wasting money, resulting in 20% fewer operations of that kind.
- <u>Technologies</u>: Nodejs, React, React-native, CSS3, Redux, PHP, MySQL.

#### AFTj Digital and Marketing Solutions

Atlanta, Georgia

Frontend Engineer (Remote)

July 2021 – Present

- Tested, coded, reviewed, and delivered software with 100% on-time record and according to service level objectives.
- Implemented performance tuning techniques on stored procedures and back-end queries which resulted in an improvement in the application performance of up to 46%.
- Utilized a responsive and mobile-first approach to streamline all offerings which increased mobile traffic by 35%.
- <u>Technologies</u>: React, Nodejs, Style-component, MySql, React-native, Tailwind, Redux, typescript, git, Jira, Jenkins, jest

#### The Root Hub

Akwa-Ibom State, Nigeria

Frontend Engineer Intern

*October* 2019 – *March* 2020

- Responsible for creating and maintaining new reports for the case support team that boost efficiency by 20%.
- Collaborated with a team of 6 other students to share ideas and experience on the use of tools like Javascript, React, and Redux.
- <u>Technologies</u>: Javascript, css3, Html, react, redux. bootstrap, git.

## **EDUCATION**

University of UyoUyo, Awka-Ibom NigeriaBSc. PhysicsJune 2014- October 2019

• Grade: Second Class Upper Division

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design (Coursera)
The Web Development Bootcamp (Udemy)

Dec. 2021

Aug. 2020